<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philip John Madeley | Interaction Designer</title>
    <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Philip John Madeley | Interaction Designer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.philipmadeley.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chatbot concept</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/flight-booking-chatbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/flight-booking-chatbot/</guid>
      <description>Overview AI technologies are still in its infancy, but with advancements in the coming years, we could start to imagine a more tailored &amp;lsquo;service&amp;rsquo; around how we do things. I decided it would be interesting to put that theory to the test through a quick design challenge around booking premium class flight tickets.
Identifying the target user Airlines managed to grow premium revenue as a share of total sales on key routes such as the transatlantic, which continues to be the biggest premium air market in the world, and also on flights between Europe and Asia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart oven</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/smart-oven-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/smart-oven-app/</guid>
      <description>Overview The connected home is becoming a reality for more and more people. This project explored a smart oven concept and some of the design implications of such an app.
Identifying the target user Since this was a quick personal project, I harvested secondary research to understand who might benefit most from using a smart oven. Here&amp;rsquo;s a TL;DR of the salient points:
 British women with children feel the most pressure to start chores, including cooking, after returning home from work Working British parents between the ages of 16-25 experience the most burnout after work The average Brit spends below 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo editing</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/google-maps-photo-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/google-maps-photo-editing/</guid>
      <description>Design Challenge I&amp;rsquo;m a big foodie, and I often add restaurant reviews to Google Maps to keep track of places I visit and help other English speakers in Tokyo (I also think it&amp;rsquo;s a great app :)
When uploading to Google Maps, the user can add a caption, however if your photos are upside down, under exposed or need cropping, then you have to open a different app to do any photo editing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User rating</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/google-maps-ugc-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/google-maps-ugc-review/</guid>
      <description>Design Challenge UGC (user-generated content) is enriching Google Maps from just a route planner before, now the app can be your guide to doing things. On the surface, looking at the rating and reading reviews can often be enough to make a yes-no decision about eating in a restaurant, drinking in a bar or entering a venue. I decided to focus on restaurants for this challenge and make the UGC more granular by quickly showing a succession of rating categories for food, service and value in addition to the overall rating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angle adjust</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/angle-adjust/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/angle-adjust/</guid>
      <description>Design Challenge I love snowboarding and wanted to capture the best footage from a day in the mountains. However, after challenging the limits of my ability, I eventually wipe out, knocking my Go Pro off angle. I decided to create a smartwatch app which enables the user to quickly check what they&amp;rsquo;re shooting and change the angle without having to pull out a phone or guess.
Design Process  Get firsthand experience of the problem Sketch out ideas and iterate on the design Move into Sketch Write down the experience from start to finish Work out if the step is an animation or user event Move to Framer and follow your written plan Test on device (if possible) Solicit feedback from community and friends  See the code on Codepen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon x Kao</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/amazon-kao/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/amazon-kao/</guid>
      <description>Overview I worked with a small cross-functional team to craft custom advertising solutions for top-tier clients in Tokyo. Kao, a major cosmetics company, wanted to increase awareness of a new fabric softener (Dress and Airy), through a custom landing page experience.
Goals Since the product was new to the market, Kao wanted to focus on two goals:
 Create brand awareness and lift Motivate the customer to buy the product  Concept We ran a design sprint and created a concept around the idea of synergy; two different products that interlinked in the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive nav scroll</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/responsive-nav-scrolling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/responsive-nav-scrolling/</guid>
      <description>Design Challenge I sometimes find the Quora app quite useful for looking up specific questions. I noticed both the header/footer nav were always present and reduced screen real estate when quickly browsing long pages. My solution was to prototype a retractable header/footer nav when an on scroll event is detected. Once the user finds something of interest and stops the page scroll, the header/footer nav reappear.
Design Process  Pick an app you like and want to improve Sketch out ideas and iterate on the design Take screenshots and recreate what you need in Sketch Write down the experience from start to finish Work out if the step is an animation or user event Move to Framer and follow your written plan Test on device (you need to get firsthand experience of your design) Solicit feedback from community and friends  Play on Framer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular carousel</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/modular-carousel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/modular-carousel/</guid>
      <description>Design Challenge Framer has been my go-to tool for interactive prototypes, however, sometimes it takes a crazy amount of code to put together an experience consisting of just a few components. My solution was to create a modular JS carousel component which could be easily reused across different projects and customized with a few variables.
Design Process  Think of a component you often use Write out what the component should do (Pseudocode if you prefer) Write your component straight into Framer (it&amp;rsquo;s much faster this way) Once your code is working, move it to a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modal slider</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/modal-slider/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/modal-slider/</guid>
      <description>Design Challenge I enjoy using Instagram, but one of my pet peeves is that you can&amp;rsquo;t (at the time of writing 2016/4/5) quickly swipe through full-screen photos. My solution was to quickly prototype a lightbox modal which chronological queues up photos so the user can swipe through each photo and return by swiping up.
Design Process  Pick an app you like and want to improve (one you know well helps) Sketch out ideas and iterate on the design Take screenshots and recreate what you need in Sketch Write down the experience from start to finish Work out if the step is an animation or user event Move to Framer and follow your written plan Test on device (you need to get firsthand experience of your design) Solicit feedback from community and friends  Play on Framer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Temp Folder Example Page This is a sample &amp;ldquo;singleton&amp;rdquo; page. The URL is decided by the title in the front matter of the markdown file. The singleton_stylesheet: in the front matter points to a corresponding file with the same name in static/css/singletons-stylesheets, which will pipe the appropriate stylesheet in after the site-wild stylesheet in cases where you make want to create one-off pages with URLs at the root of your site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Singleton</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/sample-singleton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/sample-singleton/</guid>
      <description>Temp Folder Example Page This is a sample &amp;ldquo;singleton&amp;rdquo; page. The URL is decided by the title in the front matter of the markdown file. The singleton_stylesheet: in the front matter points to a corresponding file with the same name in static/css/singletons-stylesheets, which will pipe the appropriate stylesheet in after the site-wild stylesheet in cases where you make want to create one-off pages with URLs at the root of your site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon x Level-5</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/amazon-yokai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/amazon-yokai/</guid>
      <description>Overview Yo-Kai Watch, the number-one rated cartoon sensation from creators Level-5 and media giant Dentsu, wanted to increase awareness of the upcoming movie through a custom landing page. This was a massive effort spanning numerous teams, a tie-up with Amazon Prime Video and multiple vendors of branded goods.
Goals  Increase awareness of the upcoming movie Promote Amazon Prime Video&amp;rsquo;s tie-up  Final Campaign We leveraged the two main characters for the first-view screen and focused a call-to-action button under the movie trailer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon x Kirin</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/amazon-kirin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/amazon-kirin/</guid>
      <description>Overview Kirin, a major drink manufacturer, wanted to increase awareness of a new product (Off White) through a custom landing page experience.
Goals Since the product was new to the market, Kirin wanted to focus on two goals:
 Educate the customer about the product Motivate the customer to buy the product  Concept We had great support from Kirin&amp;rsquo;s marketing team and leveraged their user research to create an immersive page around activities associated with relaxing at home after work with a beer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaps</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/metaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/metaps/</guid>
      <description>-- Overview Metaps was preparing for its IPO and required a rebranding overhaul of its flagship site. The brief was to create a multilingual, responsive site which highlighted key product features and delivered one integrated brand experience.
Ideation Our kickoff meeting looked at the metrics from the dashboard to surface popular pages and help plan out a site map. Mapping out the site on a whiteboard made it easy to visualize the basic structure and navigation required across the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spike Box</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/spikebox-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/spikebox-app/</guid>
      <description>Overview Spike Box is a social networking app and similar in concept to Craigslist but with followers. The brief was to design a simple and easy-to-understand UI, where users can easily share stuff that they don&amp;rsquo;t want anymore. The app must stand out from other competitors and create value for the user by being easy-to-use, yet engaging.
Ideation Developing a native app was a first for Metaps and we didn&amp;rsquo;t have any firsthand user data to work from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaps Analytics</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/analytics/</guid>
      <description>Overview Metaps is an app monetization platform focused on how to maximize revenue and optimize campaign performance. This was an on-going project over about 16 months which was split into two parts
 Design and implement modular components for the preexisting dashboard Redesign the landing page  In this case study I will only discuss the dashboard funnel and segment analytics tools.
Ideation Kickoff meetings were held with a product manager to figure out the goals, scope, and constraints of each project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robotics</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/robotics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/robotics/</guid>
      <description>Overview To design and code a new landing page for Metaps which introduces a business model to monetize robot development. The site must be able to communicate the company&amp;rsquo;s vision through an easy-to-understand narrative.
Ideation Robot monetization was an off-tangent business for Metaps, and blue-sky thinking was required to move the project forward. A Stakeholder map and some basic storyboarding identified use-case scenarios and how the product could relate to different user groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaps Careers</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/careers-landing-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/careers-landing-page/</guid>
      <description>Overview A careers landing page to spearhead Metap&amp;rsquo;s continued growth and recruitment of tech industry professionals. The experience had to attract potential talent, focus on Metaps roadmap for success and highlight its industry credentials.
Ideation Our kickoff meeting started with whiteboard sketches and discussed the CEO&amp;rsquo;s vision and strategy for setting the right message. We brainstormed various ideas and identified stakeholders with touchpoints of how each user group could engage with Metaps on a deeper level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Studio</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/creative-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/creative-studio/</guid>
      <description>Overview To design and develop a single page experience with unique branding to attract app developers and other potential clients. The site must showcase a variety of illustrations and communicate key features and clear service flow.
Ideation For this project, I started working with a new project leader (a crazy but very nice guy). We sat down and discussed the site&amp;rsquo;s value proposition and map out key aspects:
 what the site is who is the user how will the site be used  We narrowed down our blueprint and created a consensus — the visual impact and creativity of the site would be pivotal in engaging with our main user group – the game developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/json/site-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/json/site-index/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>