<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Works on Philip John Madeley | Interaction Designer</title>
    <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Works on Philip John Madeley | Interaction Designer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon x Kao</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/amazon-kao/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/amazon-kao/</guid>
      <description>Overview I worked with a small cross-functional team to craft custom advertising solutions for top-tier clients in Tokyo. Kao, a major cosmetics company, wanted to increase awareness of a new fabric softener (Dress and Airy), through a custom landing page experience.
Goals Since the product was new to the market, Kao wanted to focus on two goals:
 Create brand awareness and lift Motivate the customer to buy the product  Concept We ran a design sprint and created a concept around the idea of synergy; two different products that interlinked in the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon x Level-5</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/amazon-yokai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/amazon-yokai/</guid>
      <description>Overview Yo-Kai Watch, the number-one rated cartoon sensation from creators Level-5 and media giant Dentsu, wanted to increase awareness of the upcoming movie through a custom landing page. This was a massive effort spanning numerous teams, a tie-up with Amazon Prime Video and multiple vendors of branded goods.
Goals  Increase awareness of the upcoming movie Promote Amazon Prime Video&amp;rsquo;s tie-up  Final Campaign We leveraged the two main characters for the first-view screen and focused a call-to-action button under the movie trailer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon x Kirin</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/amazon-kirin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/amazon-kirin/</guid>
      <description>Overview Kirin, a major drink manufacturer, wanted to increase awareness of a new product (Off White) through a custom landing page experience.
Goals Since the product was new to the market, Kirin wanted to focus on two goals:
 Educate the customer about the product Motivate the customer to buy the product  Concept We had great support from Kirin&amp;rsquo;s marketing team and leveraged their user research to create an immersive page around activities associated with relaxing at home after work with a beer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaps</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/metaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/metaps/</guid>
      <description>-- Overview Metaps was preparing for its IPO and required a rebranding overhaul of its flagship site. The brief was to create a multilingual, responsive site which highlighted key product features and delivered one integrated brand experience.
Ideation Our kickoff meeting looked at the metrics from the dashboard to surface popular pages and help plan out a site map. Mapping out the site on a whiteboard made it easy to visualize the basic structure and navigation required across the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spike Box</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/spikebox-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/spikebox-app/</guid>
      <description>Overview Spike Box is a social networking app and similar in concept to Craigslist but with followers. The brief was to design a simple and easy-to-understand UI, where users can easily share stuff that they don&amp;rsquo;t want anymore. The app must stand out from other competitors and create value for the user by being easy-to-use, yet engaging.
Ideation Developing a native app was a first for Metaps and we didn&amp;rsquo;t have any firsthand user data to work from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaps Analytics</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/analytics/</guid>
      <description>Overview Metaps is an app monetization platform focused on how to maximize revenue and optimize campaign performance. This was an on-going project over about 16 months which was split into two parts
 Design and implement modular components for the preexisting dashboard Redesign the landing page  In this case study I will only discuss the dashboard funnel and segment analytics tools.
Ideation Kickoff meetings were held with a product manager to figure out the goals, scope, and constraints of each project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robotics</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/robotics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/robotics/</guid>
      <description>Overview To design and code a new landing page for Metaps which introduces a business model to monetize robot development. The site must be able to communicate the company&amp;rsquo;s vision through an easy-to-understand narrative.
Ideation Robot monetization was an off-tangent business for Metaps, and blue-sky thinking was required to move the project forward. A Stakeholder map and some basic storyboarding identified use-case scenarios and how the product could relate to different user groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaps Careers</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/careers-landing-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/careers-landing-page/</guid>
      <description>Overview A careers landing page to spearhead Metap&amp;rsquo;s continued growth and recruitment of tech industry professionals. The experience had to attract potential talent, focus on Metaps roadmap for success and highlight its industry credentials.
Ideation Our kickoff meeting started with whiteboard sketches and discussed the CEO&amp;rsquo;s vision and strategy for setting the right message. We brainstormed various ideas and identified stakeholders with touchpoints of how each user group could engage with Metaps on a deeper level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Studio</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/creative-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/work/creative-studio/</guid>
      <description>Overview To design and develop a single page experience with unique branding to attract app developers and other potential clients. The site must showcase a variety of illustrations and communicate key features and clear service flow.
Ideation For this project, I started working with a new project leader (a crazy but very nice guy). We sat down and discussed the site&amp;rsquo;s value proposition and map out key aspects:
 what the site is who is the user how will the site be used  We narrowed down our blueprint and created a consensus — the visual impact and creativity of the site would be pivotal in engaging with our main user group – the game developer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>