<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal-projects on Philip John Madeley | Interaction Designer</title>
    <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal-projects on Philip John Madeley | Interaction Designer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chatbot concept</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/flight-booking-chatbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/flight-booking-chatbot/</guid>
      <description>Overview AI technologies are still in its infancy, but with advancements in the coming years, we could start to imagine a more tailored &amp;lsquo;service&amp;rsquo; around how we do things. I decided it would be interesting to put that theory to the test through a quick design challenge around booking premium class flight tickets.
Identifying the target user Airlines managed to grow premium revenue as a share of total sales on key routes such as the transatlantic, which continues to be the biggest premium air market in the world, and also on flights between Europe and Asia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart oven</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/smart-oven-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/smart-oven-app/</guid>
      <description>Overview The connected home is becoming a reality for more and more people. This project explored a smart oven concept and some of the design implications of such an app.
Identifying the target user Since this was a quick personal project, I harvested secondary research to understand who might benefit most from using a smart oven. Here&amp;rsquo;s a TL;DR of the salient points:
 British women with children feel the most pressure to start chores, including cooking, after returning home from work</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food delivery</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/food-delivery-loyalty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/food-delivery-loyalty/</guid>
      <description>Overview Food delivery is heating up, globally. Deliveroo, Uber Eats, Swiggy, Amazon, and a whole lot more are fighting it out for customer loyalty. I decided to take a stab at trying to understand rewarding loyalty in this space through a design challenge.
Framing the problem For this hypothetical design challenge, I&amp;rsquo;ve conjured up a UK-based food delivery company, Chive. At some point in the future, Chive wants to treat the loyalty of their growing user base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo editing</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/google-maps-photo-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/google-maps-photo-editing/</guid>
      <description>Design Challenge I&amp;rsquo;m a big foodie, and I often add restaurant reviews to Google Maps to keep track of places I visit and help other English speakers in Tokyo (I also think it&amp;rsquo;s a great app :)
When uploading to Google Maps, the user can add a caption, however if your photos are upside down, under exposed or need cropping, then you have to open a different app to do any photo editing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User rating</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/google-maps-ugc-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/google-maps-ugc-review/</guid>
      <description>Design Challenge UGC (user-generated content) is enriching Google Maps from just a route planner before, now the app can be your guide to doing things. On the surface, looking at the rating and reading reviews can often be enough to make a yes-no decision about eating in a restaurant, drinking in a bar or entering a venue. I decided to focus on restaurants for this challenge and make the UGC more granular by quickly showing a succession of rating categories for food, service and value in addition to the overall rating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angle adjust</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/angle-adjust/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/angle-adjust/</guid>
      <description>Design Challenge I love snowboarding and wanted to capture the best footage from a day in the mountains. However, after challenging the limits of my ability, I eventually wipe out, knocking my Go Pro off angle. I decided to create a smartwatch app which enables the user to quickly check what they&amp;rsquo;re shooting and change the angle without having to pull out a phone or guess.
Design Process  Get firsthand experience of the problem</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive nav scroll</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/responsive-nav-scrolling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/responsive-nav-scrolling/</guid>
      <description>Design Challenge I sometimes find the Quora app quite useful for looking up specific questions. I noticed both the header/footer nav were always present and reduced screen real estate when quickly browsing long pages. My solution was to prototype a retractable header/footer nav when an on scroll event is detected. Once the user finds something of interest and stops the page scroll, the header/footer nav reappear.
Design Process  Pick an app you like but has something you want to improve</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular carousel</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/modular-carousel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/modular-carousel/</guid>
      <description>Design Challenge Framer has been my go-to tool for interactive prototypes, however, sometimes it takes a crazy amount of code to put together an experience consisting of just a few components. My solution was to create a modular JS carousel component which could be easily reused across different projects and customized with a few variables.
Design Process  Think of a component you often use
 Write out what the component should do (Pseudocode if you prefer)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modal slider</title>
      <link>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/modal-slider/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.philipmadeley.com/personal-projects/modal-slider/</guid>
      <description>Design Challenge I enjoy using Instagram, but one of my pet peeves is that you can&amp;rsquo;t (at the time of writing 2016/4/5) quickly swipe through full-screen photos. My solution was to quickly prototype a lightbox modal which chronological queues up photos so the user can swipe through each photo and return by swiping up.
Design Process  Pick an app you like and want to improve (one you know well helps)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>